Kirito?
Just five more minutes...
Come on.
I know it's our day of rest, but...
You sleep too much!
Good morning, Yujiro. Good morning.
Wanna go into town today?
The sun's out, and the sky's gorgeous.
To you, I'm with yourself
Shining Sun My Diamond
Damn, that's yummy.
Can't you wait till we get home? No.
They taste better when
they're fresh out of the oven.
Wanna have a bite?
No thanks, I'm good for now.
Maybe later.
Suit yourself.
Man, I can't believe how time flies.
We left Rulid, what, two years ago now?
Yeah, so much has
happened to us since then.
Let's see.
First, we went to Zakaria.
We got to hone our swordsman skills quite
a bit while living and
working on that farm.
We won the swordfighting tournament
together and joined the Zakaria garrison.
It seems like yesterday
we came to the capital
and made it into the Swordcraft Academy.
I can't get over how amazing
it is that we're even here.
Oh, come on.
It's been like a whole year
since we moved to the dorms.
You should be bored out
of your skull by now.
I guess so.
Kirito!
Lina!
What a coincidence.
Hey, good morning, ma 'am.
Good morning.
We haven't met yet.
You were you, Gio.
Is that correct?
Um, yes, ma 'am.
There's no need to be nervous.
I thought you were going home for the day.
Yes, I was just there, actually.
They sent me back to get some things.
Um, may I carry that for you?
That's very kind.
However, you're supposed to
be Golgaro Sobalto's page.
You're right.
I'm sorry.
I was out of line.
As for you, you are my page, yes?
So tell me, why is it you
didn't offer to help first?
Busted.
Oh, honestly.
I appreciate your offer
to assist me. Really.
However, I'm almost
finished with my shopping.
Besides, this is your day of rest.
You shouldn't have to think about work.
Your duty as pages will
be over soon, anyway.
Once we graduate, it's onward and upward.
If anything, I wish I
could learn more from you.
Your words are too kind.
I am blessed to be your mentor.
Thank you for everything.
It was an honor knowing you.
And an honor for me, too.
Same.
What the heck are you
getting all flustered for?
I guess it's because Sword
Alina's so beautiful.
And she's kind of intimidating, too.
Yeah, you got a point.
I'm a nervous wreck when we
spar, because she's so intense.
Gogoroso can be pretty intense, too.
In fact,
even after all the training I've had with
him, I still can't score a single point.
Same here.
Alina's always two steps ahead of me,
and she's second seat in her class.
I wonder how strong Volo is.
He's in the first seat.
Pretty strong.
Can you even imagine
beating an upperclassman?
I certainly can't.
And that there's the problem, huh?
Well, good night, Kirito. Huh? Oh, night.
After being stuck here
for the past two years,
I learned that in this world, your true
power wasn't just expressed in numbers.
Only three stats show up in your window.
Your life, your object control authority,
and your system control authority.
If your object control
authority's a low number,
you can barely even hold
a higher class weapon.
But if your stat's way bigger than
the weapons, it feels crazy light.
Your system control
authority stat That tells
you what kind of sacred arts you can use.
If you're low level, you
can only use simple spells.
But if you level up, you get
access to more sophisticated ones.
That's how it works in games too.
But there's an extra feature
here that affects your stats.
It's something SAO and AOLO didn't have.
Sometimes the strength of a mental image
you create can influence your stats.
If a person has the
confidence or will to win,
their power can be
amplified many times over.
That's what makes Lena so powerful.
She's confident because
ever since she was a kid,
she had the best training
in swordsmanship.
So if you can imagine yourself
to be more powerful than anyone,
you'll have the potential to
rewrite the laws of this world.
Oh, my God.
You win again, as always.
But you came close a
few times, didn't you?
No, it was all you.
Don't be so modest.
I know you still have some latent
power you're hiding from me.
One year ago,
I chose you for my page because I
sensed a similarity in our sword styles.
But over the course of the year,
it's become obvious how unrefined
my skills actually are. No way!
You're amazing!
In the end, I couldn't even beat
you once during our training.
For two years, give or take, there is
someone I have not managed to beat either.
Oh, you mean first seat Volo Leventayne.
Yes.
Between you and I, whenever I face
him, I falter, just like a coward.
No matter how hard I train,
I can't seem to convince myself I have the
skill or the power to withstand his sword.
Lina.
However, it is not the same
for you when you face me.
There is more to the Aincrad style
that you haven't shown me, isn't there?
So before I graduate
the day after tomorrow,
I want to know everything
you're capable of.
With this thing?
I will, but I can't right now. I'm sorry.
But if you can wait till tomorrow,
I promise I'll show you then.
The greatest sword skill I can use.
But tomorrow's a day of rest.
You know training is forbidden then.
Yeah, but it won't be training.
It'll be your...
your graduation present.
Yeah, that's it.
You can give presents on days of rest.
I've never heard of gifting sword
skills before, but if you insist...
Alright, I look forward to it. Awesome.
Tomorrow then.
Kirito is here, ma 'am!
I'm sorry I'm late, ma 'am.
Why are you 38 minutes late, Primary
Trainee Kirito? Practicing, ma 'am.
With Elite Disciple Sordalina Surlute.
Our session went longer than usual today.
I applaud your commitment
to your education.
It is your duty as a page to
learn from your mentor. However,
it seems to me that
you think your training
gives you permission to break your curfew.
Oh, of course not, Mrs. Zerica.
All I want is to get better
as a swordsman, that's all.
Me coming in after curfew is
just an accident, I swear.
Mealtime is starting in 17 minutes.
Make sure you're not late for that.
Where have you been?
Sorry, my sparring session
with Lina went long.
Yum!
I cannot tell you how
jealous I am, Lord Rios.
After we toiled so hard
cleaning this cafeteria,
they get to just waltz in and
eat as if they own the place.
I so envy their good fortune.
Now, now, Umber, don't slander.
Pages have their struggles, too.
I'm sure their duties are
beyond what even we can imagine.
I suppose you're right.
These pages have to be at
their mentor's beck and call.
Why, I heard they have to
indulge their every whim.
Could you imagine what
it must be like for them,
having a mentor from a lower-class house?
They must issue the
most outlandish orders.
Ignore those two jerks. Just eat.
Oh, I've been meaning to ask.
How's your garden coming along?
Doing pretty good so far, actually.
It should be in full bloom
in time for graduation. Nice.
Can't wait to see it.
They look like they're doing great.
They're even starting to bud.
It took three tries, but I
finally got the hang of it.
Man, I really hope this batch blooms.
It's on course, too, by the looks of it.
They're going to make a wonderful
graduation gift for Lena.
You're so thoughtful.
Give me a break.
After knowing you for the past two years,
I had no idea you liked
puttering around a garden.
Yeah, I'm as surprised
as you. You know what?
This might be a sign that
your memories are coming back.
Maybe before you came to rule
it, you used to be a gardener.
Yeah, maybe that was your calling.
Uh, yeah, maybe.
I'm, uh, gonna get some water.
Wait, what?
At some point, you may end up
getting your memory back. What then?
Huh?
What do you mean?
You're training to be an Integrity Knight.
But you're only here
because you're helping me.
I'm here because I want to find
Alice and bring her back home.
What if you remember your home?
If I do get my memory
back I ain't going home.
There's one thing I know.
I'm a swordsman.
All the way for a swordsman being
an integrity knight's a dream job.
I'm weak.
I always have been.
If I hadn't met you I don't know.
I guess I'd still be
swinging that axe right now.
Still stuck in my.
village, blaming it all on my calling.
The only reason I'm even here
is because I had you with me
to lead the way.
It's all because of you.
And just now, when you said
you wouldn't return to your
home even if you got your memory back, it
filled me with such relief. Oh, come on.
Quit your moping.
You think I could have made it all
the way to the capital by myself?
I didn't know where it was,
Plus, my memory's a blank.
And worse, I didn't have
two coins to rub together.
The only reason I'm here
now is because of you.
We make a great team.
So why mess that up?
We're better if we stick together.
We can worry about going our own ways
after we become Integrity Knights.
Deal?
Okay, deal.
First things first, though.
We have to ace this exam.
Only the top 12 will get to advance.
Yeah, well, I'm having a hard
time with my sacred art skills.
So what do you say?
Want to help your partner out?
Of course.
In fact, tomorrow's our day
of rest so we can study.
I can't.
Oh, right, I forgot.
Yep, tomorrow's the day I pick it up.
I bet you're excited.
Hell yeah, I've been waiting all year.
Can't wait to try it out.
These things don't grow on trees.
A black brick rhinestone's
supposed to last me three years.
I went through six of them this
year working on that thing.
Uh, yeah, sorry about that.
That ranch was so tough, it took me a whole
damn day just to scrape a sliver off it.
You have any idea how many hours I
spent shaving away at this thing?
The tip of the Giga-seater is the part
that absorbed all the blessings of Solus
Take it on your journey And
when you reach the capital,
go and see Sardaray, the craftsman,
and leave it in his care He'll
make a wonderful sword from it
See that?
I'm a craftsman by calling but
metalsmithing's where my heart's really...
I'm sorry.
Did you finish the sword?
Young man.
I don't remember us
talking about money yet.
Don't worry. It's okay.
Pay the man.
If you don't have enough,
I can loan you the rest.
Of course, I might let you just have it.
Huh? Huh? Really? Really.
But there's a catch.
You've got to be able
to swing this monster.
Good luck.
When I finished, I tried picking it
up, and the damn thing felt heavier.
No way. It did?
What's wrong? Draw it.
Okay, here goes.
Nice form, Kirito.
So a trainee can handle it.
Well, now I've seen everything.
It's a good sword.
Damn right it is.
Anyway, the sword's all yours.
I'm a man of my word, after all.
Thanks a lot!
Hey, I'm gonna go try this out for a bit.
Okay, just don't be late
for dinner. I won't.
This world's no game, but
it's got sword skills.
I can only do two-hit combos
with my practice sword.
Let's see what this can do.
This is great.
I can keep my promise to Lena now.
No, wait, how about a five-parter?
The blue rose sword couldn't
do one, but maybe this can.
I guess it can't.
First Seat Levantain.
I'm sorry, Elite Disciple Levantain.
I didn't mean to get dirt on your uniform.
I've seen you before.
You're Elite Disciple
Sirloot's page. Yes, sir.
Primary Trainee Kirito.
Right.
Practicing the sword is
forbidden on a day of rest.
I, um, I wasn't.
This isn't practice, sir.
Um, I was just trying out my new sword.
I couldn't wait till tomorrow.
Your test swings were, how
shall I say, enthusiastic.
You and I are similar that way.
We both search for a reason to wield
a sword, even on a day of rest.
Yearning to scratch
that itch. You too? Yes.
So I shall overlook that transgression.
You're very generous, sir.
Do not thank me yet,
Trainee Kirito. Uh, pardon?
I did not say I would
forgive you for this.
News travels fast.
Kirito!
What'd you do this time? Nothing.
Oh, well, it was a good run.
You survived a whole year here
without getting into trouble.
New record, partner.
Lord Levantain, what
is the meaning of this?
Just a minor infraction.
Your page was disrespectful to me.
Nothing that demands serious
punishment, mind you.
So we shall settle it by
sparring with real swords.
What did you say?
You don't have to worry about me, ma 'am.
Really, I can handle myself.
In fact, I sort of feel honored to get the
chance to spar with the first seed here.
Kirito, have you discussed
the rules with him yet?
No, but since we're using real
swords, isn't it stopped short?
I forgot to mention something earlier.
I do not engage in shortstop duels.
For all my personal matches, I
prefer to fight first strike.
He's never fought a
match with real swords.
Besides, you need his consent.
Of course, mine too.
This cannot proceed unless we both agree.
And if he does not, the
match will be stopped short.
Well, trainee Kirito, do you agree?
Don't do it, Kirito. Lolo's strong.
He will hurt you.
I think I'll let you
decide it, Lord Levantain.
I'm the one being punished after all.
Let's do it.
Next time, Swordsman's Pride.
Thank you.